Welcome. In the last lecture, we got hold of some climbing animations we need and starting
欢迎。在上一讲中，我们掌握了一些我们需要的攀登动画，从这一讲开始，我们将研究如何实际使用这些动画。
from this lecture, we are looking into how we can actually use these animations. So first
从这节课开始，我们将研究如何实际使用这些动画。所以首先
thing I'm going to take care of transitioning from idle to climbing and this is the animation
我将处理从空闲到爬升的过渡，这就是我将使用的动画。
that I'm going to use. So you can see it's called idle to brace the hang. And I think
这是我要使用的动画。所以你可以看到它被称为 "空闲 "以支撑悬空。而且我认为
this animation is too long. I don't need it to be this long. So I'm going to adjust it
这个动画太长了。我不需要它这么长。所以我打算调整它
a little bit. So close this window. I'm going to first go back to my animation folder. Right
一点点。所以关闭这个窗口。我将首先回到我的动画文件夹。鼠标右键
mouse button click to create a new folder. I'm going to call this one adjusted. I'm going
鼠标键点击创建一个新的文件夹。我将把这个文件夹称为 "调整"。我将
to press control plus D to duplicate this animation and I'm going to change its name
按control加D来复制这个动画，我将把它的名字改为
to idle to climb underscore adjusted. So I'm going to make all the adjustments needed to
改为 "闲置 "为 "调整 "的下划线。所以我将进行所有必要的调整，以使这个复制的动画
get this duplicated one so that we always have a backup to come back to. Alright, I'm
这样我们就有了一个备份，可以随时回来使用。好的，我将
going to move this animation to adjusted folder. Select move here, then go inside of it, double
将这个动画移到调整后的文件夹中。在这里选择移动，然后进入它的内部，双击
click to open it. So we don't need to be this long. About 20 frames would be enough. So
点击来打开它。所以我们不需要这么长。大约20帧就够了。所以
right before our character grabs the wall. Alright, something like this. I'm going to
就在我们的角色抓住墙之前。好的，像这样。我将会
right mouse button click and remove from frame 21 to 39. And next thing I'm going to scroll
鼠标右键点击，从第21帧到第39帧删除。接下来，我将向下滚动
down and take this enable root motion. The reason why I want to take this is I'm going
下去，并采取这个启用根部动作。我之所以要这样做的原因是我要
to create an anim montage based on this animation and use that anim montage to transition us
在这个动画的基础上创建一个动画蒙太奇，用这个动画蒙太奇把我们从闲置状态过渡到
from idle to climbing. Having the root motion enabled here can prevent us from moving the
从闲置状态过渡到爬升状态。在这里启用根部运动可以防止我们在蒙太奇播放时移动角色
character when the montage is playing. Alright, I'm going to close this window and right mouse
当蒙太奇正在播放时，可以防止我们移动角色。好的，我将关闭这个窗口，然后用鼠标右键
button click and select create anim montage. I'm going to rename this to am underscore
点击鼠标右键，选择创建动画蒙太奇。我将把这个重命名为am underscore
idle to climb. Then back to animation folder, create a new folder. I'm going to call it
idle to climb. 然后回到动画文件夹，创建一个新的文件夹。我将把它叫做
montages. We'll need to create different montages later. Then I'm going to move this anim montage
montages。我们以后将需要创建不同的蒙太奇。然后我将把这个动画蒙太奇
to this folder. Select move here. And there's one more thing that we need to do in order
到这个文件夹。在这里选择移动。还有一件事我们需要做，以便
to play the montage successfully. So I'm going to go back to this climb system, open this
来成功播放蒙太奇。所以我将回到这个攀登系统，打开这个
app. So I'm going to drag out a pin and I'm going to type in slot and default slot here
应用程序。所以我将拖出一个针，然后我将在这里输入插槽和默认插槽
should work since I don't plan to create other slots. And by default, an anim montage will
应该可以，因为我不打算创建其他槽。默认情况下，一个动画蒙太奇将使用
be using the default slot. So I'm going to double click to open this montage and you
使用默认的槽。所以我将双击来打开这个蒙太奇，你可以看到这里使用的是
can see in here it's using the default slot. So this should work. Alright, I'm going to
你可以在这里看到它正在使用默认槽。所以这应该可以了。好的，我将会
close this window and go to file, click save all, then close my project. Next thing we
关闭这个窗口，转到文件，点击全部保存，然后关闭我的项目。下一件事我们
need to take care of the coding part. So I'm going to right mouse button click this tab
我们需要处理编码的部分。所以我打算用鼠标右键点击这个标签
and select close all but this. And I'm going to scroll out first and I'm going to forward
并选择关闭所有内容，除了这个。我将首先滚出，我将转发
declare the type. So it's going to be class U anim montage. And I'm going to copy this
声明这个类型。所以它将是U类动画蒙太奇。我将复制这个
type, scroll down to this climb BP variables, paste the type in here and I'm going to name
类型，向下滚动到这个攀登BP变量，把这个类型粘贴到这里，然后我将命名为
this pointer idle to climb montage and I'm going to copy this U property, paste it in
我将把这个指针空闲命名为攀登蒙太奇，我将复制这个U属性，把它粘贴到
here and I'm going to scroll up to this climb core variables. So under this current climbable
我将复制这个U属性，把它粘贴到这里，然后我将向上滚动到这个攀登核心变量。所以在这个当前可爬升
surface normal, I'm going to create an empty U property and the type is going to be U anim
表面法线下，我将创建一个空的U属性，其类型将是U动画
instance. I'm going to call this owning player anim instance and we also need to forward
实例。我将会把这个拥有播放器的动画实例称为U动画，我们还需要向前
declare the type. So copy this type, paste it in here. Alright, I'm going to scroll down
声明这个类型。所以复制这个类型，把它粘贴到这里。好的，我将向下滚动
to this climb core and in here I'm going to create a new function. I'm going to call this
在这里我将创建一个新的函数。我将调用这个
function play climb montage and it's going to have one input parameter. It's going to
它将有一个输入参数。它将有一个输入参数。
be U anim montage. I'm going to call this one montage to play. So later I'm going to
是U动画蒙太奇。我将调用这一个蒙太奇来播放。所以稍后我将会
use this function to play all the montages needed and I'm going to create a function
使用这个函数来播放所有需要的蒙太奇，我将创建一个函数
definition press control plus K control plus O to go to the CPP file. I'm going to go to
定义按control plus K control plus O进入CPP文件。我将去到
the bottom of it and paste the function in here and to play the montage we'll need to
要播放蒙太奇，我们需要得到有效的动画实例，并将其粘贴在这里。
get hold of the valid anim instance and I like to do that in begin play. So go back to
为了播放蒙太奇，我们需要掌握有效的动画实例，我喜欢在开始播放时这样做。所以请回到
the header file above this tick component. I'm going to create a new function. It's going
头文件，在这个tick组件上面。我将创建一个新的函数。它将会是
to be virtual void. It's going to be begin play and I'm going to mark it as override
它将是虚拟无效的。它将会是begin play，我将会把它标记为override
and create a function definition place the function above this tick component. So go
并创建一个函数定义，把这个函数放在这个tick组件上面。所以去
to the top and place it in here. First thing I'm going to call super and copy this game
到顶部，把它放在这里。首先，我将调用super并复制这个游戏
play. So instead of begin play I'm going to access the variable character owner and use
播放。所以我将访问变量character owner并使用get mesh和get anim instance函数来代替beginning play。
the function get mesh and get anim instance. And I'm going to store the value inside of
函数get mesh和get anim instance。我将把这个值存储在我们创建的变量中。
the variable that we created. So it will be owning player anim instance and that's it.
我们创建的变量里面。所以它将是拥有玩家的动画实例，就这样了。
Then I'm going to go back to this play montage function. So first thing I'm going to check
然后我将回到这个播放蒙太奇的函数。所以我首先要检查
if montage to play is not valid. I'm going to return then if owning player anim instance
如果要播放的蒙太奇是无效的。如果拥有的播放器动画实例无效，我将返回
is not valid I'm going to return as well. Then the third check so if I'm going to copy this
是无效的，我也会返回。然后第三项检查，如果我打算复制这个
owning anim instance. So if there's any montage playing I'm going to return as well. So by
拥有的动画实例。所以如果有任何蒙太奇正在播放，我也会返回。所以通过
doing this we won't be able to interrupt other montages. Alright once we get past these three
这样做，我们就不能打断其他蒙太奇。好了，一旦我们通过了这三个
if checks I'm going to use the function owning player anim instance and call the function
如果检查，我将使用拥有播放器动画实例的函数并调用函数
montage underscore play and fill in this montage to play. And I have some red squiggles and
montage underscore play并填入这个蒙太奇播放。我有一些红色的斜线
that's because I have a typo for this anim montage. So I'm going to select this type
那是因为我在这个动画蒙太奇中出现了一个错字。所以我将选择这个类型
press control plus F to search and I'm going to replace it you anim montage. So it's TA
按control加F键搜索，我要把它换成动画蒙太奇。所以它是TA
not AD and change this to current project and select find next and change this one as well
不是AD，把这个改成当前项目，然后选择查找下一个，把这个也改了。
change this one change this one and that's pretty much it. Now I'm going to go back to
改变这个项目，改变这个项目，这就差不多了。现在我将回到
my cpp file and I'm going to try to compile. I have a successful compile. So far we've
我的cpp文件并尝试编译。我有一个成功的编译。到目前为止，我们已经
only set up the function to play the montage but we haven't really played the idle to climb
到目前为止，我们只设置了播放蒙太奇的功能，但我们还没有真正播放空闲的爬坡动作。
montage and I like to do that inside of toggle climbing. So I'm going to go to the top of
蒙太奇，而我喜欢在切换攀登中做这个。所以我要去到这个cpp文件的顶部向上滚动。
this cpp file scroll up. So this is our toggle climbing. Now if this can start climbing is
这个cpp文件的顶部向上滚动。这就是我们的切换式攀登。现在，如果这个可以开始攀登是
true instead of directly calling start climbing I'm going to delete this function. I'm going
true，而不是直接调用start climbing，我将删除这个函数。我将会
to call the function play climb montage and fill in this idle to climb montage. So if
调用play climb montage这个函数，并把这个空闲填到 climb montage。所以，如果
we can start climbing I want to enter the climb state when we finish playing this montage.
我们可以开始攀登，我想在我们播放完这个蒙太奇后进入攀登状态。
But how can we know when the montage is finished playing? Well there's a delegate inside of
但是我们怎么能知道蒙太奇什么时候播放完了呢？好吧，在一个实例的内部有一个委托。
an instance that we can use. So I'm going to scroll up to begin play. Right after we
的一个委托，我们可以使用它。所以我要向上滚动，开始播放。就在我们
get hold of this owning player in instance I'm going to check. So if this owning player
掌握了这个拥有播放器的实例后，我就会进行检查。所以如果这个拥有播放器的
in an instance is true then I'm going to access the delegate inside. So the name is called
实例是真的，那么我就会访问里面的委托。所以这个名字叫做
own montage ended. So this is the delegate that we need to bind to and I'm going to use
own montage ended. 所以这就是我们需要绑定的委托，我将会使用
the helper macro add dynamic to help us to bind the function needed and fill in this.
我将使用辅助宏add dynamic来帮助我们绑定所需的函数，并填入这个。
And the second input parameter will be the address of our member function. Let's find
而第二个输入参数将是我们的成员函数的地址。让我们找出
out the requirements for it. So I'm going to select this own montage ended press F12
的要求。所以我将选择这个自己的蒙太奇结束按F12
to go to its definition. Then I'm going to select this type. So it's called own montage
转到它的定义。然后我将选择这个类型。所以它被称为自己的蒙太奇
ended MC delegate and press F12 again. So you can see this is a dynamic multicast delegate.
结束的MC委托，再按F12。所以你可以看到这是一个动态组播委托。
It has two parameters. So our member function needs to have you and a montage and a boolean
它有两个参数。所以我们的成员函数需要有你和一个蒙太奇和一个布尔值
as input parameters. So I'm going to copy this go back to my header file and under display
作为输入参数。所以我要把这个复制到我的头文件中，并在display
climb montage function I'm going to create a U function. So we need to have a U function
攀登蒙太奇函数，我将创建一个U函数。所以我们需要有一个U函数
in order to have a successful binding for a multicast delegate. So it needs to be void.
以便成功绑定一个多播委托。所以它需要是无效的。
I'm going to call this one own climb montage ended and paste these function inputs and
我将调用这个自己的攀登蒙太奇结束，并粘贴这些函数输入，并删除我们不需要的东西。
delete the things we don't need. And I'm going to create a function definition and place
删除那些我们不需要的东西。我将创建一个函数定义，并将其放在
the function below this play client montage paste it in here. I'm going to copy the address
把这个函数放在这个播放客户端蒙太奇的下面，把它粘贴在这里。我将复制这个函数的地址
of this function then fill in in here. I have a title for a dynamic. I mean, I fixed that
这个函数的地址，然后填在这里。我有一个动态的标题。我的意思是，我固定了这个
and besides this own montage ended there's another one that I want to bind to. So I'm
除了这个自己的蒙太奇结束，还有一个我想绑定的。所以我
going to select this and I'm instance and the second delegate is called own montage
我要选择这个，我的实例和第二个委托被称为自己的蒙太奇
blending out and the rest is going to be the same as this one above. So I'm going to copy
融合，其余的将和上面这个一样。所以我将复制
this and paste it in here. All right. I'm going to compile first to see if there are any errors.
并把它粘贴到这里。好的。我先编译一下，看看是否有什么错误。
All right. I have a successful compile. So this function will be called when a montage
好的。我有一个成功的编译。所以这个函数将在一个蒙太奇结束时被调用
has ended. So for that I'm going to print a debug message for now. So it can be debug
结束时调用这个函数。所以为此我打算暂时打印一个调试信息。所以它可以是debug
print and the message is going to be climbed montage ended and I'm going to launch my editor
print，这个信息将是攀升的蒙太奇结束，我将启动我的编辑器
back. I have a back inside of my editor. I'm going to go back to this climb system, open
返回。我的编辑器里面有一个返回。我将回到这个攀登系统，打开
this BP character and open for blueprint editor. So first thing I'm going to assign a valid
这个BP角色并打开蓝图编辑器。所以我首先要在蓝图中指定一个有效的
montage inside of the blueprint. So for this idle to climb, I'm going to select this idle
蒙太奇在蓝图中。因此，为了让这个空闲的人攀爬，我将选择这个空闲的人
to climb and press compile. Now I'm going to press play and go to a climb both surface.
攀爬，然后按编译。现在我将按下播放键，并进入一个爬升的两个表面。
Press F and you can see we are playing a montage in here and that's great. And we have debug
按F键，你可以看到我们在这里播放一个蒙太奇，这很好。而且我们有调试
message printed to the screen. Great. Everything is working. Later when you are doing this
信息打印到屏幕上。很好。一切都在工作。以后你在做这个的时候
yourself, if for some reason you cannot play your montage, double check if you have created
你自己，如果因为某些原因你不能播放你的蒙太奇，请仔细检查你是否在动画蓝图中创建了一个槽。
a slot in animation blueprint and if the function binding is not working, make sure you have
动画蓝图中的槽，如果函数绑定不起作用，请确保你有回调函数的U函数宏。
the U function macro for the callback function and don't forget to assign montage in your
确保你有回调函数的U函数宏，不要忘记在你的蓝图中指定蒙太奇。
blueprint. All right. It's time for you to do the same and I'll see you in the next lecture.
蓝图中指定蒙太奇。好了。现在是你做同样事情的时候了，我们在下一个讲座中再见。
[Music]
[音乐]